A Revolution Has Begun...
Tremors 4: The Legend Begins is a action, comedy,
horror film directed by S.S. Wilson.
In 1889, seventeen men die under mysterious circumstances, and spooked by recent events, the miners who
populate the town leave in droves until there's nothing left but a shell of a community.
Hiram Gummer, played by Michael Gross.
Christine Lord, played by Sara Botsford.
Black Hand Kelly, played by Billy Drago.
Juan Pedilla, played by Brent Roam.
Tecopa, played by August Schellenberg.
Old Fred, played by J.E. Freeman.
Tremors 4: The Legend Begins is a 2004
direct-to-video horror Western film directed by S.
Wilson and written by Brent Maddock, Nancy Roberts, and Wilson.
It is the fourth film in the Tremors series of films
and released on DVD on January 2, 2004.
As a prequel to the earlier films and television series, it depicts the town of Rejection, which is the
location that would later be renamed Perfection, the main setting for the first Tremors film.
It stars Michael Gross as Hiram Gummer, the great grandfather of the character
Burt Gummer, who Gross portrayed in every other Tremors film.
The film explores themes of small town, miner, creature, graboids, giant worm.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.